Guide to the Phoebe Jacobs Jazz collection,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Jazz Musicians
  - Subseries III.1: Louis Armstrong
    - Sub-subsubseries III.1.4: Clippings
      - Murray, Albert Periodical clipping: "The Wild Words of Louis Armstrong", The New Republic: Washington D.C., 22 November 1999, (2 copies ) (Box 12, Folder 215)
        [Article exploring Armstrong's personal writings]
      - Morgenstern, Dan "Louis Armstrong: An American Genius, Book Review", [n.p.], 1983, (4 pages ) (Box 12, Folder 216)
        [Periodical source unidentified.]
      - Articles printed and faxed from unidentified sources re: Louis Armstrong, [v.p.], [n.d.] 1995-1999, (1 folder ) (Box 12, Folder 217)
      - Sacred Heart of Jesus Church "A Music Tribute to Louis Armstrong": notes, flyers, and correspondence, New Orleans, LA, 25 August 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 12, Folder 218)
      - Louis Armstrong International Airport Clippings and programs regarding the naming of Louis Armstrong International Airport, New Orleans, LA, August 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 229)
    - Sub-subsubseries III.1.5: Louis Armstrong Centennial
      - Newspaper and periodical clippings, [n.p.], 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 223)
      - Armstrong related newspaper clippings during the Armstrong centennial, [v.p.], 2000, (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - Louis Armstrong Educational Foundation Flyers and press releases regarding Centennial activities, Queens, New York, 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 225)
      - Newspaper clippings regarding New Orleans Centennial Tribute, New Orleans, LA, 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 227)
      - New Orleans Centennial Tribute to Armstrong: flyers, programs and general information regarding New Orleans, New Orleans, LA, 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 228)
      - University of New Orleans Materials regarding centennial celebration, New Orleans, LA, August 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 230)
    - Sub-subseries III.1.6: Miscellaneous
      - Promotional materials for the Louis Armstrong Jazz Curriculum Project, Lincoln Center: New York, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 231)
      - Lists of music recordings. [n.p.], 1951-1955, (8 pages t.ms. 1 page carbon copy ) (Box 1, Folder 16)
        [Dates refer to recording dates.]
      - Louis Armstrong Stamp Collection, New Orleans, LA, 1 September 1995, (2 packets ) (Box 5, Folder 108)
      - Miscellaneous printed materials regarding Armstrong's life, [v.p.], (1 folder ) (Box 5, Folder 106)
      - Queens College of the City University of New York Materials: "Satchmo's Students: The 'Pops' Project", New York, Fall 1997, (1 folder ) (Box 4, Folder 98)
      - Miscellaneous Louis Armstrong materials, [n.p.], (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 232)
      - U.S. Postal Service First day of use envelopes with Louis Armstrong stamps, New Orleans, LA, 1 September 1995, (14 postmarked envelopes ) (Box 11, Folder 195)
        [Envelopes unused]
      - Armstrong, Louis and Lucille Unaddressed Christmas card, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 card ) (Box 11, Folder 198)
      - Miscellaneous artwork related to Louis Armstrong, [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 x 6 3/4 inches color ink sketch s. 8 1/2 x 11 inches ink line drawing s. ) (Box 11, Folder 203)
        [Signatures: "Sir Shadow"; other unclear]
      - Assorted, unused postcards of Louis Armstrong, [n.p.], [n.d.], (10 p.c. black and white ) (Box 12, Folder 221)
      - Programs, flyers, and press releases, [n.p.], 2001, (1 folder ) (Box 13, Folder 224)
      - Jones, Lisa L. Antiquarian catalogue containing ad with Louis Armstrong's watch, [n.p.], 2001, (1 vol. bd. 1 a.n.s. ) (Box 13, Folder 226)
  - Sunseries III.2: James Hubert "Eubie" Blake
    - Short biographical write up [unsigned]; record reviews and periodical clippings, [v.p.], [n.d.] 1973-1983, (5 items ) (Box 6, Folder 136)
    - Promotional materials: recording pamphlets, programs for "Brunch with the Blakes" at the Rainbow Room and Carnegie Hall event, New York, 1980, (5 items ) (Box 6, Folder 137)
    - Invitation and menus from White House luncheon celebrating Blake's receipt of the Presidential Medal of Freedom; photographs of Blake with President Reagan and First Lady Nancy Reagan; memento napkin, Washington D.C., Sept 1981, (8 items 2 color photographs 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - Invitations to Blake's 100th birthday party; admission tickets, Shubert Theatre, New York, 7 February 1983, (1 card 6 tickets 2, envelopes ) (Box 6, Folder 140)
    - Blake, Marion T. Memorial service programs; one undated and unsigned open letter detailing her last years, New York, [n.d.]; 6 July 1982, (3 programs 2 t.l. ) (Box 6, Folder 139)
    - United States Army Band Program: An Evening with Eubie Blake, An American Classic, Lincoln Center, New York, 12 June 1982, (1 program ) (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - James Hubert "Eubie" Blake Memorial service programs, St. Peter's Church, New York, 18 February 1983, (10 programs ) (Box 6, Folder 142)
      [Remarks given by Gregory Hines]
    - Events in Blake's name: New York Centennial Ragtime Celebration; 108th anniversary celebration, New York, 1991-1997, (2 items ) (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - Assorted photographs of Blake, [n.p.], [n.d.] 11980, 1982, (8 snapshots 3 photographs 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - Robert Walker Two photographs of Blake's head as sculpted by the artist Walker; three photographs of hands, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3black and white photographs, 5 x 7 inches 3 color photographs, 3 1/2 x 5 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 145)
      [Medium unidentified, possibly wood or ]
    - Biographical manuscripts with notes, Beverly Hills, CA, [n.d.], (2 pages t.ms. 1 page a.ms. ) (Box 15, Folder 284)
      [Author unidentified]
    - The New York Times Article "24 Hours of Jazz to Celebrate 100 Years of Eubie Blake" with short vita attached, New York, 4 February 1983, (5 photocopies ) (Box 15, Folder 285)
    - Times-Union Article "They're Just Wild about Eubie Blake", [n.p.], 1982, (1 page ) (Box 15, Folder 286)
    - Bolcom, William Rolling Stone Magazine Obituary "Eubie Blake: February 7th, 1883-February 12, 1983", [n.p.], 31 March 1983, (1 page ) (Box 15, Folder 287)
    - Snapshots of "Eubie" Blake from unidentified occasion at "Red Blazer", [n.p.], (8 color photographs, 3 1/2 x 5 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 288)
      [With Buddy Tate, Louis and Phoebe Jacobs, Muriel Zuckerman, ]
    - Miscellaneous snapshots of "Eubie" Blake, New York, 1978-1983, (4 color photographs, 3 1/2 x 4 1/2 inches ) (Box 15, Folder 289)
      [With Lucille Armstrong, Phoebe Jacobs, and Robert Merrill]
  - Subseries III.3: Duke Ellington
    - Sub-subsubseries III.3.1: General
      - Correspondence and contracts regarding biography of Duke Ellington by his granddaughter, Mercedes Ellington. Primary authors include Marshall Lee from Balance House Ltd. (the book's publisher), Mercedes Ellington, and Phoebe Jacobs; excerpts from manuscript, New York, 1998-1999, (1 folder ) (Box 2, Folder 26)
        [ RESTRICTED ACCESS TO THESE MATERIALS]
      - Assorted Duke Ellington education related materials: Duke Ellington School for the Arts, Duke Ellington Education Kit., [n.p.], 1997-1998, (1 folder ) (Box 3, Folder 44)
        [Including newspaper articles, curriculum guide, concert programs, and promotional material]
      - The Washington Post Article: "Students Honor Duke with a Song", Smithsonian National Museum of History, Washington, D.C., 25 April 1998, (2 pages photocopies ) (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - Ellington Memorial items: map and description of Woodlawn Cemetary; postcard photograph with sculpture of Ellington to be placed in London's Soho Square, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 flyers 1 postcard ) (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - New York Times "Ellington Gives Wisconsin His Music and Thoughts", [n.p.], 23 July 1972, (1 page ) (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - New York World Telegram and Sun Newspaper clipping: "Girl Joins the Duke's Peerage.", New York, 10 January 1964, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - Downbeat Magazine Newspaper clipping: "Love You Madly", [n.p.], 25 April [1974?], (7 pages photocopy 7 pages photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 52)
        [Birthday letters and notes to Duke Ellington sent in from readers; one from Frank Sinatra]
      - Magazine clippings: advertising for Olivetti typewriters and Mademoiselle fashion spread, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages ) (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - Horizon Magazine clipping: "Duke's Sweet Thunder: Five years after his death, Ellington is ordained as a great American composer", [n.p.], November 1979, (1 page ) (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - The New York Times Newspaper clipping: "Smithsonian Acquires Duke Ellington Trove of Scores and Papers"; itinerary of exhibition travel dates, Washington D.C., 27 April 1988, (1 page 2 pages ) (Box 3, Folder 55)
      - Mark Feeney The Boston Globe Magazine Magazine clipping: "Duke: 20 years after Duke Ellington's death, his music is thriving", [n.p.], 19 December 1993, (6 pages photocopy 6 pages photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - Mitch Baranowski Spirit Magazine Magazine clipping (incomplete), [n.p.], June 1999, (1 page ) (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - Young, Noel Night & Day Magazine article: "The Duke's Daughter", [n.p.], 9 April 2000, (3 pages ) (Box 3, Folder 58)
        [Article regarding controversial Ellington biography claiming Ellington's younger sister Ruth was in fact his daughter.]
      - U.S. Department of State Flyer with biography of Duke Ellington's work among others, [n.p.], February 1965 copyright, (3 pages photocopy 3 pages photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 60)
        [Titled: "Cultural Presentations Program of the U.S. Department of State, 1 July 1963-30 June 1964: A Report to the Congress and the Public by the Advisory Committe on Arts." ]
      - Biographical notes and miscellaneous memoir, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 pages 1 page a.ms. ) (Box 3, Folder 61)
        [Handwritten page does not appear to be Ellington's handwriting]
      - New York Public Library Program, opening invitations, and press release regarding library exhibit: "Love You Madly: A Celebration of Duke Ellington", New York, 10 July-18 August 1979, (5 programs 3 note cards 2, pages t.ms. ) (Box 3, Folder 63)
      - TDES, Inc. Newsletters, New York, 1995-1998, (7 items ) (Box 3, Folder 64)
        [Organization dedicated to Ellington's work]
      - Programs, flyers, and announcements regarding Ellington tributes, [v.p.], 1995-2000, (8 items ) (Box 3, Folder 65)
      - Duke Ellington Ellington memorial postage stamps, [n.p.], 29 April 1986, (3 envelopes ) (Box 14, Folder 254)
      - American Music Theater Festival Program "Duke Ellington's Queenie Pie", PA, 18-28 September 1986, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 14, Folder 255)
      - Duke Ellington Memorial Fund, Inc. Flyers, New York, NY, [n.d.], (5 flyers ) (Box 14, Folder 256)
      - New York University Flyer "Tribute to Edward Kennedy Duke Ellington", New York, NY, 1-22 February 1999, (1 flyer ) (Box 14, Folder 257)
      - Providence Public Library Flyer: The Duke Ellington Orchestra, directed by Mercer Ellington, Providence, RI, 7 April 1995, (1 flyer 2 envelopes ) (Box 14, Folder 258)
      - Jacobs, Phoebe Ellington on Ellington: press release by Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 pages t.ms. ) (Box 14, Folder 259)
      - Cohen, Harvey Masters Thesis: "The Marketing of Duke Ellington", [n.p.], 12 April 1996, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 14, Folder 261)
      - "Duke Ellington in Flight", [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 vol. bd. 1 page a.ms. ) (Box 14, Folder 262)
        [Unfilled book and contents list in unidentified hand]
      - Nixon, Richard Presidental Award to Edward Kennedy Ellington, Washington D.C., 29 April 1969, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 14, Folder 263)
      - Jazz at Lincoln Center Program and press releases regarding Ellington Centennial Festival, New York, 1998, (4 items ) (Box 14, Folder 240)
      - Duke Ellington Youth Project Curriculum Guide Activities List, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 14, Folder 239)
        [No indication of what organization sponsored and arranged the selections]
      - The Duke Ellington Society [TDES, Inc.] Programs and newsletters, New York, 1995-1998, (12 items ) (Box 14, Folder 238)
      - U.S. Postal Service Duke Ellington memorial stamps, New Orleans, LA, 1 September 1995, (8 unused stamps 1 postmarked envelope 1, announcement ) (Box 11, Folder 196)
    - Sub-subseries III.3.2: Clippings
      - Feeney, Mark Article "Duke: 20 Years after Duke Ellington's death, his music is thriving", The Boston Globe Magazine: Boston, MA, 19 December 1993, (1 vol. bd. 5 pages photocopies ) (Box 14, Folder 241)
      - Charles A. Moses Press release regarding Ellington rights released for "Broadway Swings" revue, Burbank, CA, 23 March 1995, (1 page t.ms. ) (Box 14, Folder 242)
      - Schirmer News Article "Hall of Fame" with Ellington's listing, New York, NY, 6 March 1998, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 14, Folder 243)
      - Tom Harris Duke Ellington International Conference Formal conference notes and press release, Chicago, IL, 6-10 May 1998, (2 pages t.ms. 3 pages facsimile ) (Box 14, Folder 244)
      - Museum News "The Duke's Festival", [n.p.], July/August 1998, (4 pages photocopies ) (Box 14, Folder 245)
        [Regarding Ellington Collection at the National Museum of American History]
      - Thomas, Greg The Black World Today "Historic Collaboration Honors Duke Ellington", [n.p.], 14 April 1999, (3 pages photocopies ) (Box 14, Folder 246)
        [Web magazine: www.tbwt.com/views/feat/feat1074.asp]
      - Holmes, Emory Los Angeles Times: Sunday Calendar "The Duke of L.A.", Los Angeles, CA, 25 April 1999, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 14, Folder 247)
      - Swed, Mark Los Angeles Times "Duke's Singular Genius", Los Angeles, CA, 5 May 1999, (2 pages ) (Box 14, Folder 248)
      - Fernandez, Enrique Sun-Sentinal "Jazz Ruled the Century, and The Duke Ruled Jazz", South FL, 31 May 1999, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 14, Folder 249)
      - The New Yorker "The Theatre: Saluting the Duke", New York, NY, 16 March 1981, (1 page ) (Box 14, Folder 252)
      - The New Yorker "Jazz: Ellington Theatre", New York, NY, 9 November 1981, (2 pages ) (Box 14, Folder 253)
    - Sub-subseries III.3.3: Eve Ellis Ellington
      - Copy of Eve Ellis Ellington's will and the court's final judgment on her estate by the Surrogate's Court of New York County, State of New York; photocopies of correspondence and checks regarding Phoebe Jacobs' inheritance from Eve Ellis Ellington's will., 1978, (1 folder ) (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Eve Ellis Ellington Eve Ellis Ellington's will, 1976, (5 bound documents ) (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - Eve Ellis Ellington Last will and testament; unused personal check, New York, 20 January 1976, (7 pages t.ms.s. ) (Box 14, Folder 233)
    - Sub-subseries III.3.4: Mercedes Ellington
      - Mercedes Ellington To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], 6 January 1999, (1 page a.ms.s. ) (Box 3, Folder 35)
        [Regarding financial transactions and Duke Ellington biography project.]
      - TV Guide Article: "Mercedes Ellington Leads Duke Ellington Orchestra", [n.p.], 8 April 1996, (1 page photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - Mercedes Ellington Contracts and correspondence, [v.p.], [n.d.] 1996-1998, (12 pages photocopies ) (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - Mercedes Ellington To Phoebe Jacobs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2pages a.ms.s. ) (Box 2, Folder 32)
        [Correspondence regarding professional frustration with Winton Marsalis and Lincoln Center.]
      - Mercedes Ellington Promotional materials: clippings, photographs, promotional biography, [n.p.], [n.d.] 1999-2000, (1 folder 2 photographs; head shots, 8 1/2 x 11 inches ) (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - Garment, Leonard Dechert Price & Rhoads To Mercedes Ellington, Washington D.C., 23 October 1997, (3 pages facsimile ) (Box 2, Folder 30)
        [Unsigned draft of fax regarding the legal disputes of the Duke Ellington heirs.]
      - Ellington, Mercedes Materials regarding book "Uncle Edward: A Duke Ellington Album": press releases, correspondence, notes, contracts, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 14, Folder 234)
      - Ellington, Mercedes Press vita and related articles, [v.p.], [n.d.] 1999-2000, (4 items ) (Box 14, Folder 235)
    - Sub-subseries III.3.5: Mercer Ellington
      - Receipts from Phoebe Jacobs and Mercer Ellington. Most relate to expenses incurred by or for the promotion of the Duke Ellington Orchestra and/or Mercer Ellington, [n.p.], [n.d.] 1993-1996, (1 folder ) (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Assorted correspondence about, to, or from Mercer Ellington, [n.p.], [n.d.]; 1982-1995, (1 folder ) (Box 3, Folder 38)
        [Includes one page typed draft of biographical notes.]
      - Mercer Kennedy Ellington Last Will and Testament, Circuit Court, Oakaloosa County, Florida, 6 June 1996, (9 pages photocopy ) (Box 3, Folder 40)
        [Date reflects the filed date in Okaloosa County, Florida]
      - Mercer Ellington Typed manuscripts "Ellington on Ellington" in 2 sections; copies of article "What it's like working with the Duke.", New York, [n.d.], (25 pages t.ms. photocopies 2 pages photocopies ) (Box 3, Folder 39)
        [Article identified: "A daily critique by WWD."]
      - Press release, concert announcement for Duke Ellington Orchestra conducted by Mercer Ellington; business cards for the orchestra, [v.p.], 1996, (2 pages 4 cards ) (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - Ellington, Mercer Copies of vita and article regarding professional activities, [n.p.], [n.d.] 1993, (1 folder ) (Box 14, Folder 237)
    - Sub-subseries III.3.6: Photographs
      - Ellington, Duke Ellington in live performance with horn players and vocalist, [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 black and white photographs, 6 3/4 x 9 1/2 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 264)
      - Publicity photographs of Ellington alone or with unidentified, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 black and white photographs, 8 1/2 x 10 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 265)
      - Ellington with Eve Ellis Ellington, [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 black and white photographs, 8 x 10 inches 1 photo negative ) (Box 14, Folder 266)
      - Ellington with Mercedes and Mercer Ellington, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 color photograph, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 267)
      - Ellington with unidentified woman, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 268)
      - Photograph with Willie B at Watkins's Basin Street East, New York, NY, 1961, (1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 269)
      - Photograph of youthful Ellington at piano, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 270)
      - Book Duke Ellington; volume with photographs, Gil Kravette: Irvington, NJ, [n.d.], (1 vol. bd. ) (Folder OVERSIZE OVERSIZE)
      - Ellington, Duke Color slides, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 2 x 2 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 362)
      - Ellington, Duke Negative, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 4 1/4 x 5 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 363)
      - Ellington, Duke Glossy photocopy, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 black and white, 8 1/2 x 11 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 364)
        [With unidentified man and woman]
      - Glaser, Joe Color snapshots, New York, 1972; [n.d.], (1 4 x 4 inches 1 2 1/2 x 3 1/2 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 365)
        [Publicity agent for Duke Ellington; one includes Mercer Ellington and others]
      - DeSayles, Sylvia Color photographs, New York, [n.d.], (3 4 x 5 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 366)
        [Singer with Duke Ellington; At Ralph Watkins Basin Street East]
      - Ellington, Mercer Black and white publicity photographs, [n.p.], [n.d.], (4 photographs, 7 x 9 1/4 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 367)
        [Conducting at unidentified awards ceremony]
      - Ellington, Mercer Color slides, [n.p.], [n.d.], (18 2 x 2 inches ) (Box 18, Folder 368)
      - Photographs: Ellington at the piano surrounded by young people, [n.p.], [n.d.], (10 photographs 8 1/2 x 11 inches; black and white ) (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - Photographs: snapshot sized. Identified persons are Adelaide Hall and Rachel Edelson (Benny Goodman's daughter)., [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 photographs; 4 x 6 inches 1 photograph; 4 x 4 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - Photograph: Duke Ellington at piano surrounded by unidentified adults, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 photograph 8 1/2 x 11 inches; black and white ) (Box 3, Folder 47)
        [Stamped: "From the the Collection of Eve Ellis Ellington."]
      - Photograph: Duke Ellington with Eve Ellis Ellington and birthday cake, New York City, [n.d.], (1 photograph 81/2 x 11 inches; black and white ) (Box 3, Folder 48)
        [Note on verso: "Evie Ellis Ellington and Duke, A birthday Celebration in Ralph Watkins' Basin Street, Broadway and 50th Street, NYC."]
      - Photograph: Ellington's Third Sacred Concert at St. John of the Divine; with press release, New York City, [n.d.], (1 photograph 9 1/4 x 11 3/4 inches; black and white 1 page ) (Box 3, Folder 49)
        [Release: "Duke Ellington's Third Sacred Concert to Have American Premiere."]
      - Ellington, Mercedes Snapshots at Ellington gravesite and Lincoln Center, New York, [n.d.], (20 color photographs 4 x 6 inches ) (Box 14, Folder 236)
      - Color slides, [n.p.], [n.d.]; 1974, (6 slides 2 x 2 inches ) (Box 3, Folder 50)
        [With handwritten notes on 5: "Duke - Africa"; "Duke and young lady"; "Duke and Priest"; and "Duke entering an Embassy." ]
      - Laser printed photos of Ellington with Evie Ellis Ellington; Ellington at the piano; Ellington on stage with band, [n.p.], [n.d.], (3 pages ) (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Subseries III.4: Ella Fitzgerald
    - Sub-subseries III.4.1: General
      - Program for Ella Fitzgerald's 75th birthday tribute, New York, NY, 2 February 1993, (1 program 1 envelope ) (Box 15, Folder 272)
        [Handwritten note "I am producer of this event." Phoebe Jacobs]
      - Birthday Tribute book concerning Ella Fitzgerald with notes from famous personalities, Los Angeles, 28 April 1989, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 6, Folder 124)
      - Ella Fitzgerald Computer printout of memories of Ella Fitzgerald on her death, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 folder ) (Box 6, Folder 125)
      - Ella Fitzgerald New Year card signed "Love, Ella", [n.p.], 1995, (1 card s. ) (Box 6, Folder 126)
      - Dodson, Howard To Phoebe Jacobs, New York, 10 August 1998, (2 pages t.l.s. ) (Box 6, Folder 127)
        [The New York Black 100" exhibition invitation; Ella Fitzgerald listed as one of 100]
      - National Museum of National History Press materials for museum oral history project concerning Ella Fitzgerald; includes request for interview with Jacobs, New York, 1997-1998, (1 folder 1 photobraph 8 x 10 inches ) (Box 6, Folder 128)
      - Ella Fitzgerald Press materials for television biography "Forever Ella"; materials for the making of the film, California and New York, 1996-2000, (1 folder ) (Box 6, Folder 129)
      - Eye Research Institute of Retina Foundation "Night for Light" benefit with Ella Fitzgerald, New York, NY, 20 October 1981, (1 program ) (Box 15, Folder 273)
      - Ella Fitzgerald Diabetes Interdisciplinary Research Program Brochure, CA, 1990, (1 brochure ) (Box 15, Folder 274)
      - Ella Fitzgerald Charitable Foundation Event notice and press release, Duarte, CA, 6 March 1999, (1 card 2 pages t.ms. ) (Box 15, Folder 275 14)
    - Sub-subseries III.4.2: Clippings
      - People Magazine Notice of Fitzgerald's award: "Woman of the Year" at Hasty Pudding Theatricals, Cambridge, MA, 1 March 1982, (1 vol. bd. ) (Box 15, Folder 276)
      - Ella Fitzgerald The Columbus Dispatch Newspaper clipping:The glare of the spotlight, Columbus, OH, 11 May 1986, (1 page ) (Box 6, Folder 119)
        [With sizeable photo]
      - Los Angeles Times Newspaper clipping concerning Ella Fitzgerald: "Quintessential Jazz Singer Made the Song the Star", Los Angeles, 16 June 1996, (1 page ) (Box 6, Folder 120)